since welcome to my channel wealth
creator today we'll go to the
performance review for pew for FY 2024
the ICICI Lombard so the here it goes so
that we know that I say Lombard is one
of the India's largest private insurance
companies so it provides insurance
solutions to the two wheelers car travel
health home and my right so we'll go
through each of them in detail so it's
insurance solution is broadly
categorized into four categories
the first one is Corporate Solutions
Group government business group retail
group and the shared services so so the
first corporate solutions group
it provides the insurance solutions to
the corporates to the small and medium
and micro enterprises so its focus for
the insurance solutions are for the fire
main engineering liability group
insurance and for the group health and
personal accidents so the government
business group it provides insulins
solutions to the state central and the
rural customers so it focuses its
insurance solutions for the crop cattle
mass health and personal accidents and
for the retail section
it focuses its insurance solutions on
health motor home insurance travel cyber
and personal accidents for it Hayes also
provides reinsurance and some other
insurance products go through their
product mix it mainly consists of the
motor insurance is the highest part of
the product mix with twenty four percent
and then with 21 percent consists of
motor third-party and marine and so and
so forth so it consists of two hundred
and sixty five number of branches it has
currently operating with nine hundred
and ten number of virtual offices
and it has a network of 7800 so it has a
total headcount of employees with 10,000
197 and then it has a network with
hospitals of 5025 so which is a very
good sign so and we can see the
ownership structure of the complete the
company so the I say sale um but the
promoters has a highest share holding of
fifty five point eight seven and which
is a very good sign and then we can say
the public shareholding is at forty four
point one seven so it's not bad so
promoters are at upper hand with fifty
five point eight seven
so when a structure looks good so now we
will see about the product mix with
mainly if you see from FY 18 FY 19 and a
five twenty so the product makes for the
mortar owner damage has been increased
and we can see the same for the motor
third-party and then in the health
travel and personal accidents it's
increased from 20 to 25 percent which is
a very good sign and then the fire has
been fire insurance has been increased
from 7 to 12 percent so which is fine so
it's all in a very good sign of growing
for the 2020 20 and then we'll see about
the financial results how it looks like
so though the profit and loss has been
little bit reduced from 29,000 411 weeks
are in lakhs to 28,000 193 so little bit
the profits are little reduced so but so
overall looks fine very stable company
so very strong balance sheet so we'll go
with other performance ratios so the
return on average equity has been
increased from 14.5 percent to 18 point
eight which is a very good sign and then
the combined ratio is 99th with now
hundred percent which is good so now if
we see the growth the growth has
increased from three point four five
percent to three point seven one which
is very good so everything is in
increase as part of ratios and
the investment so the what the I say
Lombard does is the money that it gets
as a insurance premiums they invest
those in the corporate bonds gone med
securities and equities so that return
has reduced from nine point four percent
to seven point nine percent yet that's
because of gold and some market movement
so so that keep that keeps on
fluctuating based on the market so so
that's a part of that investment and
then we all know that the insurance
business is growing day by day and in
India it's just penetrated to zero point
nine seven so it's a high scope that in
the future years
we might grow in a very rapid way and
all the Indians citizenship will go for
the insurance either with health or
motor or in other sections as well so
there is a lot of scope for the private
insurance companies and then we will see
about the ICICI Lombard how the stock
price is moving up so it has touched a
lower point eight eight hundred rupees
the tape mass you sell off with it has a
top of fourteen hundred over here and
then the stock price has been falling
down to approximately eighteen eight
hundred rupees and then from there it is
screened in rising trend so now it's at
290 which is little bit expensive so so
we should we will see now what are the
best prices to catch the stock and buy
it and then hold it for long term so
we'll see about the piece now so I see a
Lombard is competing with HDFC life
insurance
Bajaj finsih and then with SB a life
insurance we can see over here it has a
a p/e ratio of 55% and price-to-book
ratio of ten point three three and
dividend dividend yield is not bad it's
four point
0.46% so so the piece looks little bit
high when compared to Bajaj Finn so so
budget Windsor is also a market leader
in motor insurance and yeah not bad but
if it if we get it it'll lower P it's
definitely a good buy and then we will
see the prices at which we can catch
this talk and we can go for the buy so
we can see that there's a privates
private point which is 12 1 6 the the
stock price a bow is overboard and it's
expensive so the if we can buy this
stock at a lower price than 12 16 which
is at 11
97 or 11:44 then it's definitely a buy
signal for this ICICI Lombard which is
very good for the long term so thank you